

# LORELEI CRETU

PRODUCT MANAGER

# CONTACT

480.258.8489

LORELEI22@GMAIL.COM

WWW.LORELEICRETU.COM

### EDUCATION

# **B.A. COMMUNICATIONS**

Arizona State University 2004 - 2008

# **B.S. INTERNATIONAL STUDIES**

Arizona State University 2004 - 2008

# TRAINING

Project Management (PMP class)

Intro to Marketing
Wharton (Coursera)

**Business Metrics**Duke University (Coursera)

Learn SQL (CodeCademy)

SQL: Table Transformation (CodeCademy)

SQL: Business Metrics (CodeCademy)

**Product Design**Google (Udacity)

**UX Master Course** (Udemy)

# ABOUT

From a start-up to working at one of the top 10 U.S. media companies, have acquired over 13 years of experience in product, project and content management, as well as business analysis and web design.

Believe that a great product lies at the intersection of users' needs and a relentless team.

# EXPERIENCE

#### PRODUCT MANAGER

GANNETT | 2014 - PRESENT

- Work with key business stakeholders to define product strategy, requirements/ user stories and KPIs; prioritize sprint backlog and optimize roadmap; track and report product performance metrics, trends and competition; and maintain clear communication while leading distributed agile design and development teams to ensure we deliver quality features on time
- Launched more than a dozen B2C and internal products that generated nearly \$10M in revenue and reached new target audiences
- Founded internal program to foster innovation that allows product, project managers, designers and developers to dedicate up to 20% of their time on creative solutions, learn new skills or test new processes
- Implemented a new JIRA workflow to maximize efficiency across multiple remote teams and make it easier to train new hires, interns
- As a product and project manager led team that created a custom content management system to support nearly 20 markets for local Ted-like storytelling events and the best local businesses in a city
- Launched campaign site to promote voting that is an INMA Global Media Awards finalist, was featured on ABC's "Good Morning America" and in Times Square, and garnered celebrities' support
- Led efforts in creating mapping tool to fix SQL table names and values that resulted in company-wide database restructuring initiative and new data validation methods to ensure accurate API feed imports

# SR. DIGITAL MANAGER

AZCENTRAL.COM | 2012-2014

- Managed team of 9 producers and interns for the Entertainment,
   Lifestyle and Travel sections of azcentral.com
- Generated Omniture analytics reports and helped train editors and reporters in creating content based on their performance metrics
- Organized training for over 200 people on new content management system, as well as led efforts in converting features department to online-first news coverage
- Product owner for updates to former azcentral.com native apps (iOS, Android, iPad) that increased traffic by 17% within a week
- Led digital initiatives and content strategy that resulted in a 30% year-over-year growth
- Implemented SEO techniques that increased traffic by 55%
- Created content tool that increased azcentral.com traffic by 35%

### AWARDS & HONORS

GANNETT Creative problem solving Winner, 2016

> Innovation Finalist. 2012 + 2013

Leadership Development 2013

AZCENTRAL.COM Employee of the year 2012 + 2013

# INTERESTS

Traveling, kickboxing, dancing, novels, superhero movies, tinkering with gadgets and software, always learning, photography, music, and fashion.

# **CAN'T LIVE WITHOUT**

My iPhone, Kindle, Google.com, and french press.

MULTI-LINGUAL
English, Romanian, Spanish,
Italian

#### **DIGITAL PRODUCER**

AZCENTRAL.COM | 2008-2012

- Produced content and managed the Entertainment & Lifestyle social media accounts, increasing followers by 70%
- Assigned interns and freelancers weekly photo assignments and reached out to local public relations firms for photos that lead to a 24% decrease on budget spent on photo assignments
- Coordinated media coverage for "X-Men Origins: Wolverine" world premiere in Tempe, "So You Think You Can Dance" Phoenix auditions and "American Idol" Phoenix auditions

#### **EVENT COORDINATOR**

LIVING SOCIAL | 2011

#### **WEB DESIGNER**

FREELANCER | 2007 - 2008

#### **WEB DESIGNER**

DSI/SEGWAY OF PHOENIX | 2004-2008

- Created and maintained the e-commerce and corporate websites, wrote and edited product copy, instructions and press releases for its OEM/ODM products, as well as took product photos
- Designed ads, brochures, logos, blog graphics, posters, and packaging
- Managed the eBay and Amazon Marketplace e-commerce stores, handled sales and customer support
- Helped organize Segway of Phoenix promotional events such as Arizona Cardinals football players racetrack event and Segway tours at the J.W. Marriott Hotel in Scottsdale

# SKILLS & TOOLS

- Product/project management: JIRA, Basecamp, Trello
- Product requirements: Confluence, Google Docs
- Product roadmap: Roadmunk
- UI/UX design: Balsamiq, Sketch, Photoshop, Invision
- Analytics: Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics, Domo, AppAnnie
- User research: Typeform, SurveyMonkey, Formstack, Polldaddy
- HTML/CSS: Atom, Dreamweaver
- Code management: Github
- Mindmapping: Popplet
- A/B testing: Optimizely
- Newsletter management: Exact Target